Studer, Norman; Papers apap116
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Downtown Community School, ca. 1944-1973; Undated; 3; 3.65 cubic ft.
  - Administration, ca. 1944-1973; Undated; 3.1
    - 5th Annual Inter-School Conference, 1954 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 1)
    - 20th Anniversary Essay/Speech, ca. 1965 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 2)
    - 20th Anniversary Dinner Dance Honoring Norman Studer and Irene Neurath, 1965 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 3)
    - 25th Anniversary Yearbook, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 4)
    - 1960-1964 Graduates and High School Selections, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 5)
    - Accounting-Billing, 1965; 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 6)
    - Administrative and Personnel Issues - [RESTRICTED], 1965; 1969-1970; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 7)
    - Admissions, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 8)
    - Alumni Correspondence and Updates, 1962-1963; 1968; 1976-1977; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 9)
    - Alumni List, ca. 1962 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 10)
    - Alumni Parents' Committee, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 11)
    - American Experience from Sources, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 12-13)
    - Board of Trustees, "68 Revolution", 1967-1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 14)
    - Board of Trustees, "68 Revolution", 1968-1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 15)
    - Board of Trustees, Conflicts, 1968 April 03 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 16)
    - Board of Trustees, Crisis Meeting and Future Role of Norman Studer, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 17)
    - Board of Trustees, General Correspondence - [RESTRICTED], 1968-1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 18)
    - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 19)
    - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Materials, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 20-22)
    - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 23)
    - Board of Trustees, Meeting Notices, 1967-1968; 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 24)
    - Board of Trustees, Nursery School, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 25)
    - Brochures, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 26)
    - Budgets, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 27)
    - Building Committee, 1967; 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 28)
    - By-Laws Revisions, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 29)
    - Children's Book in Intergroup Relations, 1956 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 30)
    - Chronology and List of Famous Parents, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 31)
    - Class Rosters, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 32)
    - Class Rosters, 1963-1964; 1967-1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 33)
    - Communications Committee, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 34)
    - Community Action Freedom School, Englewood and PS 41 and JHS 3 Boycotts, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 35)
    - Consultants, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 36)
    - Contract with Parents, ca. 1960s (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 37)
    - Controversial Issues at Downtown Community School, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 38)
    - Core Curriculum 1, Junior High School, 1962; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 39)
    - Core Curriculum, Notes, 1960; 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 40)
    - Curriculum, 7th Grade Social Studies Test, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 41)
    - Curriculum, 7th and 8th grade, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 42)
    - Curriculum, 8th Grade, Delaware County, 1967; 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 43)
    - Curriculum, 8th Grade Reading and Writing, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 44)
    - Curriculum, Architecture, New York, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 45)
    - Curriculum, Art, 1961-1963; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 46)
    - Curriculum, The Catskills, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 47)
    - Curriculum, Creative Writing, 1954; 1962; 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 48)
    - Curriculum Handbook, Discipline and Appendix, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 49)
    - Curriculum, Humanities Core Program, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 50)
    - Curriculum Outline, 1966-1967; 1969-1970; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 51)
    - Curriculum, Poetry, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 52)
    - DCS as Cooperative, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 53)
    - "DCS: Cooperative Community or Bureaucratic Corporation?", ca. 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 54)
    - DCS Fair, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 55)
    - Death of Stephen Rinaldi and Subsequent Lawsuit, 1963-1965; 1967-1968; 1971; 1973; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 1)
    - Delinquent Account Guidelines - [RESTRICTED], 1969-1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 2)
    - Director, Communication with Parents, Board and Staff, 1968-1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 3)
    - Downtown Paper #1: Agenda for the 70s, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 4)
    - Downtown Paper #2: Children Read Their Landscape, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 5)
    - Downtown Paper #4: The Future of Intergroup Education at Downtown Community School, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 6)
    - The Downtowner, 1956; 1962-1964; 1967; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 7)
    - Enrollment, 1948; 1966-1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 8)
    - Education Committee, 1962; 1968-1969 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 9)
    - Enrollment Committee, Admission Policy, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 10)
    - Enrollment Committee, Admissions Controversy, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 11)
    - Evaluation Panel, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 12)
    - Finale - [RESTRICTED], 1968-1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 13)
    - Financial Statements, 1964-1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 14)
    - Fire Drill Procedures, 1961 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 15)
    - Focus of Educational Development Through the Years, Prepared by Norman Studer, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 16)
    - Goals in Education for the Coming School Year, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 17)
    - A Handbook for Parents, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 18)
    - History of the Downtown Community School, ca. 1944; 1964; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 19)
    - Ideas for Supervision, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 20)
    - "In Memory of Una Buxenbaum", 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 21)
    - Insurance Policies, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 22)
    - Integration, 1965; 1968; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 23)
    - Interculture and Intercultural Committee, 1953; 1956-1957; 1960; 1968; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 24)
    - Jane Reed Library of Americana, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 25)
    - List of Official DCS Periodic Corporate Reports, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 26)
    - The Local Scene, American Experience from Sources, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 27-28)
    - Nancy Bloch Library and Book Award, 1951; 1955-1958; 1961-1962; 1965-1969; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 29)
    - Newsletter with Biographical Sketch of Norman Studer, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 30)
    - Nominating Committee, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 31)
    - Norman Studer Speaks, 1964 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 32)
    - Office Reorganization, 1969-1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 33)
    - Orange Co. Agriculture Extension, 1964; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 34)
    - Parent Grievance Committee, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 35)
    - Parent Inactivity, 1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 36)
    - Parent Representatives, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 37)
    - Personnel Lists, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 38)
    - A Plan for DCS, 1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 39)
    - Policy and Organizational Jurisdiction, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 40)
    - Proposals for a Conference and Dinner Celebrating a Quarter Century of Education for Community Living at Downtown Community School, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 41)
    - Reports to the Board, 1965; 1969-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 42)
    - Staff, Terence Barrell, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 43)
    - Student Problems - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 44)
    - Suggested Inventory of Social Living in the School Community, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 45)
    - Suggestion to Establish a Parent Organization at DCS, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 46)
    - Teacher Contract, 1967; 1969-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 47)
    - Teacher's Guide, 8th Grade Geography, 1967 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 48)
    - Teacher's Guide, American History, ca. 1966; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 49)
    - Teacher's Guide, Catskills Trip, 1969; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 50)
    - Teacher's Guide, Folklore, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 51)
    - Teacher's Guide, Slavery, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 52)
    - Teacher's Guide, Slavery and Early New York History, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 53-54)
    - Teacher's Handbook, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 55)
    - Teaching Writing, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 56)
    - Tuition, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 57)
    - Tuition Aid - [RESTRICTED], 1968-1969; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 58)
    - Union Relations - [RESTRICTED], 1961; 1963; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 59)
    - "What does the Nursery School Teacher Teach?" by Elizabeth Doak, 1951 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 60)
    - Yearbooks, 1948; 1951-1952 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 61)
  - Activities, 1945-1971; Undated; 3.2
    The Activities subseries contains material produced by or involving the students of the Downtown Community School, as well as Norman Studer, beyond his administrative responsibilities. Materials include notes from field trips, graduation dramas, student writings, and Downtown Community School publications, the Downtowner and Scribbler. The Downtowner was an internally published periodical containing a calendar of events, an editorial from Studer, announcements, and student writings. The Scribbler differed in that it was solely composed of student writings from each grade level. This subseries is particularly strong in its representation of field trips sponsored by Studer, many of which were taken to the Catskill Mountains. The folders often include itineraries, curricular guides, local history and maps, as well as student reflections and drawings. Many of the Downtown Community School graduation dramas were predicated on the field trip experiences. Also of interest are a number of folders containing general student writings and drawings and a file on the successful 1965 efforts by the children to help save the historic Old Merchant's House in New York City from demolition.
    - Architecture Tour, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 1)
    - Calendar of Events for 25th Anniversary Year, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 2)
    - CITY DAY, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 3)
    - Class Trip Reports, Grades 1-4, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 4)
    - Dairy Farm Visit Recollections, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 5)
    - Downtown Walks, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 6)
    - E-Day Landmark Walk, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 7)
    - Efforts to Establish Sojourner Truth Memorial by Downtown Community School, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 8)
    - Efforts to Save Old Merchant's House, 1965; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 9)
    - Embroideries by Leslie Dublin, ca. 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 10)
    - Field Trips, 5th Grade Trip to Pennsylvania, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 11)
    - Field Trips, 6th Grade Trip to Pennsylvania, 1954; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 12)
    - Field Trips, 6th Grade Trip to Orange and Ulster Countries, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 13)
    - Field Trips, 7th Grade, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 14)
    - Field Trips, 7th Grade Cooperstown and Hurley Trip, 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 15)
    - Field Trips, Bus Duties and Committee Forms, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 16)
    - Field Trips, Catskills including Related Curriculum, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 17)
    - Field Trips, Great Swamp, 1962; 1964-1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 18)
    - Field Trips Moods and Landscapes - Delaware County, Sketches and Writings by 8th Grade, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 19-22)
    - Field Trips, New Jersey, 1964; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 23)
    - Field Trips, Staten Island, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 24)
    - Field Trips, Wallkill Valley Ecology Trip, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 25)
    - General Writings about Field Trips Undertaken, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 26)
    - Graduation Play, 1960 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 27)
    - Graduation Play, "Big Mose, New York's Own Paul Bunyan", 1965 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 28)
    - Graduation Play, "Tim Horn Rebellion," and Graduation Program, 1955 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 29)
    - Hand Me Downs, collected by the 7th and 8th Grades, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 30)
    - High Rock Park Nature Conservation Center, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 31)
    - "How Can We Best Educate to Eliminate Racism," Forum Moderated by Norman Studer, 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 32)
    - Intercultural Workshops, 1945; 1953-1955; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 33)
    - Intergroup Education Conference, 1958-1963 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 34)
    - Ledger with Accounting Notes from 7th and 8th Grade Field Trips, 1966-1968 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 35)
    - Leonard Covello Lectures, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 36)
    - Map of Field Trip by Danny Conrad and Kara Yeargans, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
    - Outline of Study of Staten Island, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 37)
    - "Parents Work" by Class 2L, 1964 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 38)
    - Photographs of New York City by Student, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 39)
    - The Pioneer Museum at the Downtown Community School, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 40)
    - Plays, "Sojourner Truth", 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 41)
    - Plays About Staten Island, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 42)
    - Plays, "The Days of the Tall Ships," "Twilight in the Dust Bowl'" "The Sun Goes Down on the Medicine Man," "The Story of a Piece of Pink Cotton," and "The Dark Nights of Slavery", Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 43)
    - Program for Graduation Exercises including Play "The Tredwell House", 1963 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 44)
    - Program for Graduation Exercises including Play "The Truth Shall Set You Free", 1956 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 45)
    - Program of the Black Studies Workshops, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 46)
    - Proposed Freedom Walk for Lower Manhattan, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 47)
    - Red Thunder Cloud, 1970; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 48)
    - Revolution Walk, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 49)
    - Round Table on City Folklore and Its Uses, Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 50)
    - Scribbler, 1959-1963; 1965 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 51)
    - Sleepy Hollow Restorations, 1967 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 52)
    - Sojourner Truth, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 53)
    - The Stoop, 1971 (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 54)
    - Student Reflections of New York City, 1964; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 55)
    - Student Sketches (1 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 56)
    - Student Sketches (2 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 1)
    - Student Writings, Black Studies, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 2)
    - Student Writings, Catskills, 1962; 1970; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 3)
    - Student Writings, City People, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 4)
    - Student Writings, City Talk, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 5)
    - Student Writings, Cooperstown Trip, 1952 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 6)
    - Student Writings, Collected Folklore, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 7)
    - Student Writings, Family, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 8)
    - Student Writings, Living History, Short Stories, Plays and Songs by 8th Graders in Creative Writing Class, 1961-1964; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 9)
    - Student Writings, Moods and Moments, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 10)
    - Student Writings, New Jersey, 1960; 1962; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 11)
    - Student Writings, New York City, 1969; Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 12)
    - Student Writings, Pets, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 13)
    - Student Writings, Poems about Sojourner Truth, 7th Grade, ca. 1959 (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 14)
    - Student Writings, Poetry, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 15)
    - Student Writings, Short Stories, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 16)
    - Students Writings, Songs, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 17)
    - Student Writings, Sounds of the City, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 18)
    - Student Writings, Stories Based, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 19)
    - Student Writings, Students Who Lived Elsewhere, Undated (Box 2 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 20)
    - Student Writings, Summer Camp, Undated (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 1)
    - Student Writings, Trips to Pennsylvania, 1954; Undated (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 2)
    - Student Writings, Unbound Notebook of poems, Drawings and Stories, Mr. Mogil's Class, 1969 (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 3)
    - Workshop for Democracy, 1945 (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 4)
    - Westchester County Sheep to Shawl Event, 1969 (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 5)
    - Untitled Play, Undated (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 6)
    - Trip Menu, 1965 (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 7)
    - Tours of Harlem, 1968-1970 (Box 3 (3-Downtown Community School), Folder 8)
- Camp Woodland, 1938-2012; Undated; 4; 3.26 cubic ft.
  Norman Studer, Rose Sydney, Regine Dicker (Ferber), Sara Abelson (Abramson), and Hannah Studer, founded Camp Woodland in Phoenicia, New York in 1940. Norman Studer served as camp director until 1962. A 1963 fire destroyed the camp buildings.
  This series is divided into three subseries - Administration, Activities, and Post-Camp.
  - Administration, 1938-1963; Undated; 4.1
    The Administration subseries documents the functions of the director, Board of Trustees, and staff of Camp Woodland as they relate to the operation of the Camp. Materials include annual reports, meeting minutes, correspondence, litigation, counselor in training handbooks, as well as documents related to the Larkin Committee and an investigation of Norman Studer and Camp Woodland for possible subversive activities and ties to the Communist Party. The annual reports provide fiscal summary data related to the operation of the Camp, including, but not limited to, tuition costs, expenditures, operating costs, tax liability, fixed assets and accumulated depreciation, and accumulated funds. These reports were prepared by certified public accountants and record the fiscal state of Camp Woodland in great detail. The folder entitled "Board of Director's Dispute" documents an effort by three of Camp Woodland's founders and Board members - Mrs. Ferber, Mrs. Sydney, and Mrs. Abramson - to separate themselves, legally and financially, from the Camp. It is unclear what precipitated the dispute, but ultimately, it appears there were philosophical differences as well as divergent financial interests.